with a roll of the dice, in a bride who'd been left at the alter. But it turns out, this "new" human diagnosis was neither new, nor was it uniquely human. Veterinarians had been diagnosing, treating and even preventing emotionally induced symptoms in animals ranging from monkeys to flamingos, from to deer to rabbits, since the 1970s. How many human lives might have been saved if this veterinary knowledge had been put into the hands of E.R. docs and cardiologists? Self-injury. Some human patients harm themselves. Some pluck out patches of hair, others actually cut themselves. Some animal patients also harm themselves. There are birds that pluck out feathers. There are stallions that repetitively bite their flanks until they bleed. But veterinarians have very specific and very effective ways of treating and even preventing self-injury in their self-injuring animals. Shouldn't this veterinary knowledge be put into the hands of psychotherapists and parents and patients struggling with self-injury? Postpartum depression and postpartum psychosis. Sometimes, soon after giving birth, some women become depressed, and sometimes they become seriously depressed and even psychotic. They may neglect their newborn, and in some extreme cases, even harm the child. Equine veterinarians also know that occasionally, a mare, soon after giving birth, will neglect the foal, refusing to nurse, and in some instances, kick the foal, even to death. But veterinarians have devised an intervention to deal with this foal rejection syndrome that involves increasing oxytocin in the mare. Oxytocin is the bonding hormone, and this leads to renewed interest, on the part of the mare, in her foal. Shouldn't this information be put into the hands of ob/gyn's and family doctors and patients who are struggling with postpartum depression and psychosis? Well, despite all of this promise, unfortunately the gulf between our fields remains large. To explain it, I'm afraid I'm going to have to air some dirty laundry. Some physicians can be real snobs about doctors who are not M.D.'s. I'm talking about dentists and optometrists and psychologists, but maybe especially animal doctors. Of course, most physicians don't realize that it is harder to get into vet school these days than medical school, and that when we go to medical school, we learn everything there is to know about one species, Homo sapiens, but veterinarians need to learn about health and disease in mammals, amphibians, reptiles, fish and birds. So I don't blame the vets for feeling annoyed by my profession's condescension and ignorance. But here's one from the vets: What do you call a veterinarian who can only take care of one species? A physician. (Laughter) Closing the gap has become a passion for me, and I'm doing this through programs like Darwin on Rounds at UCLA, where we're bringing animal experts and evolutionary biologists and embedding them on our medical teams with our interns and our residents. And through Zoobiquity conferences, where we bring medical schools together with veterinary schools for collabortive discussions of the shared diseases and disorders of animal and human patients. At Zoobiquity conferences, participants learn how treating breast cancer in a tiger can help us better treat breast cancer in a kindergarten teacher; how understanding polycystic overies in a Holstein cow can help us better take care of a dance instructor with painful periods; and how better understanding the treatment of separation anxiety in a high-strung Sheltie can help an anxious young child struggling with his first days of school. In the United States and now internationally, at Zoobiquity conferences physicians and veterinarians check their attitudes and their preconceptions at the door and come together as colleagues, as peers, as doctors. After all, we humans are animals, too, and it's time for us physicians to embrace our patients' and our own animal natures and join veterinarians in a species-spanning approach to health. Because it turns out, some of the best and most humanistic medicine is being practiced by doctors whose patients aren't human. And one of the best ways we can take care of the human patient is by paying close attention to how all the other patients on the planet live, grow, get sick and heal. Thank you. (Applause).
en una tirada de dados. En una novia que habían plantado en el altar. Pero resulta que, este "nuevo" diagnóstico humano no era ni nuevo, ni tampoco era exclusivamente humano. Los veterinarios había diagnosticado, tratado e incluso prevenido síntomas inducidos emocionalmente en animales, desde monos a flamencos, desde ciervos a conejos, desde la década de 1970. ¿Cuántas vidas humanas podrían haberse salvado si este conocimiento veterinario hubiera estado en las manos de paramédicos y cardiólogos? Autolesión. Algunos pacientes humanos se hieren a sí mismos. Algunos se arrancan el cabello, otros realmente se cortan a sí mismos. Algunos pacientes animales también se dañan a sí mismos. Hay pájaros que se arrancan plumas. Hay corceles que repetidamente se muerden sus flancos hasta sangrar. Pero los veterinarios tienen métodos muy específicos y muy eficaces para tratar e incluso prevenir la autolesión en sus animales que se autolesionan. ¿No se debería ponerse este conocimiento veterinario en manos de psicoterapeutas y padres y pacientes que luchan contra la autolesión? Depresión postparto y psicosis postparto. A veces, poco después de dar a luz, algunas mujeres se deprimen, y a veces se deprimen mucho e incluso se vuelven psicóticas. Pueden descuidar su recién nacido, y en algunos casos extremos, incluso dañar al niño. Los veterinarios equinos también saben que de vez en cuando, una yegua, poco después de dar a luz, descuidará el potro, negándose a lactar, y en algunos casos, patean al potro, incluso hasta la muerte. Pero los veterinarios han ideado una intervención para tratar este síndrome de rechazo al potro que implica el aumento de la oxitocina en la yegua, la oxitocina es la hormona de la unión, y esto lleva a un renovado interés, por parte de la yegua, en su potro. ¿No debería esta información estar en manos de obstetras y ginecólogos y los médicos de familia y pacientes que están luchando con la depresión postparto y la psicosis? A pesar de esta promesa, por desgracia, el abismo entre nuestros campos sigue siendo grande. Para explicarlo, me temo que voy a tener que sacar unos trapos al sol. Algunos médicos pueden ser unos verdaderos esnobs con los profesionales que no son médicos. Estoy hablando de los dentistas y lo optometristas y los psicólogos, pero quizás especialmente los médicos de los animales. Por supuesto, la mayoría de los médicos no saben que es más difícil entrar en la escuela de veterinaria en estos días que a la de medicina, y que cuando vamos a la escuela de medicina, nos enteramos de todo lo que hay que saber sobre una especie, el Homo sapiens, pero los veterinarios deben aprender acerca de la salud y la enfermedad en mamíferos, anfibios, reptiles, peces y aves. Así que no culpo a los veterinarios por sentirse molestos por la condescendencia y la ignorancia de mi profesión. Pero esto es de los veterinarios: ¿Cómo llamas a un veterinario que solo puede atender a una especie? Un médico. (Risas) Cerrar la brecha se ha convertido en una pasión para mí, y estoy haciendo esto a través de programas como Darwin en Rondas de la UCLA, donde estamos trayendo expertos en animales y biólogos evolutivos y los juntamos en nuestros equipos médicos con nuestros pasantes y nuestros residentes. Y a través de las conferencias Zoobiquity, donde juntamos las escuelas de medicina, con las escuelas de veterinaria para discusiones colaborativas sobre las enfermedades y los trastornos que comparten los pacientes humanos y los animales. En las conferencias Zoobiquity, los participantes aprenden cómo el tratar el cáncer de mama en un tigre puede ayudar a mejorar el tratamiento contra el cáncer de mama en una maestra de preescolar; cómo el entender los ovarios poliquísticos en una vaca Holstein nos puede ayudar a tratar mejor a una instructora de baile con períodos dolorosos; y cómo el comprender mejor el tratamiento de la ansiedad por separación en un perro pastor hipertenso puede ayudar a un niño ansioso que lucha con sus primeros días de clase. En los EUA y ahora internacionalmente, en las conferencias Zoobiquity los médicos y los veterinarios dejan sus actitudes y sus preconcepciones en la puerta y entran juntos como colegas, como compañeros, como médicos. Después de todo, nosotros los humanos también somos animales, y es hora de que nosotros los médicos aceptemos la naturaleza animal de nosotros y de nuestros pacientes y nos unamos a los veterinarios en un enfoque de la salud expandido de las especies. Porque resulta que, algunos de las mejores y más humanistas medicinas se practica por los médicos cuyos pacientes no son humanos. Y una de las mejores maneras en que podemos tratar al paciente humano es prestando mucha atención a cómo todos los otros pacientes en el planeta viven, crecen, enferman y sanan. Gracias. (Aplausos)